Cody Zuschlag

Senior Software Engineer

American Citizen
French Residence Permit
English (Native) and French Languages

+33 7 86 65 94 37 cody.zuschlag@gmail.com https://github.com/codyzu

PROFILE

A node.js expert specializing in back-end services including REST API's, micro-service architecture, and relational and NoSQL databases. I am a highly motivated, hard working, professional engineer with a passion for communication, open source, and all things node.js who thrives in a challenging team orientated work environment.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Node.js:

npm, es2016, babel, hapi, express, mocha, istanbul, gulp, pouchdb, offline-first

Languages:

JavaScript, Java, C#, C++, C, Objective-C, Python, Groovy HTML, CSS, JSON, XML, YML, ASP.NET UML, PL/SQL, Bash, ADO.NET, Lua

Software:

Atom, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclispse, Visual Studio, IAR-EWARM Jenkins, Maven, Sonar, NuGet, Git, Subversion InfluxDB, Grafana, Graphite Docker, VMWare ESXi, Ansible, Kubernetis Microsoft Office, SharePoint, Enterprise Architect, VersionOne, PhotoShop, Gimp

Hardware:

Logic synthesis for FPGAs and PLDs in VHDL, Verilog, Schematic Quartus 2, Leonardo Spectrum, and Modelsim USB, Ethernet, I2C, SPI, CAN, LIN, Serial

Operating Systems:

Microsoft Windows, Windows Server, Windows Compacted Embedded Apple Mac OS X, iOS Unix, Linux, Ubuntu, Arch, Debian, CentOS, openSUSE, QNX

CARREER SUMMARY

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Axway, Annecy-le-Vieux, France

SOLUTION DEVELOPER
BeauTec, Epagny, France

SENIOR FIRMWARE ENGINEER
Hamilton Company, Reno, Nevada, U.S.A.

FIRMWARE ENGINEER
International Game Technology, Reno, Nevada, U.S.A.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering Technology 2007
Top of class with honors and multiple awards for academic excellence
OREGON INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
Klamath Falls, Oregon, U.S.A.

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Technology 2007
Top of class with honors and multiple awards for academic excellence
OREGON INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
Klamath Falls, Oregon, U.S.A.

24 rue Henry Bordeaux 74000 Annecy, France

Professional Experience

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

AXWAY, Annecy-le-Vieux, France, June 2013 – present

Market leader in software and services that govern the flow of data

- Developed node.js back-end micro-services delivered in docker images for cloud deployment (using Kanban methodology).
- Presented and facilitated workshops to train employees to use new node.js technologies (including migrating services from express to hapi).
- Developed and tested user stories for a large scale OSGi and MongoDB based web application written in Java, JavaScript (backbone and jQuery), HTML5, and CSS (less) (using Agile Scrum methodology).
- Architected a performance testing strategy and led a team of developers in its implementation (using on-site VMWare ESXi servers and Amazon AWS cloud). Visualized performance results with InfluxDB and Grafana.
- Designed, implemented, and led an automated migration for a major version change with a team of developers.
- Developed test tooling in Python and BDD (jBehave).
- Authored a Capacity Planning Guide that provided recommendations for large scale deployments based on performance test results.

SOLUTION DEVELOPER

BEAUTEC, Epagny, France, March 2011 – February 2013

Developer and vendor of integration software and solutions, specializing in the petroleum refinement industry

- Developed modular integration software based on .NET technologies (C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, and SQL Server).
- Interfaced to business logic implemented in PL/SQL (Oracle DB).
- Developed ADO.NET interfaces to 3rd party libraries (SAP, OPC, SciForma, and OSISoft Pi System) that were consumed in a modular integration solution.
- Developed custom integration solutions in Java and ported applications to iOS (Objective-C).
- Implementation of work process improvements including continuous integration, distributed source control, and style guides.

SENIOR FIRMWARE ENGINEER

HAMILTON COMPANY, Reno, Nevada, U.S.A., January 2009 – February 2011

Designer, developer, and manufacturer of precision liquid handling robotics (laboratory and manufacturing instruments)

- Developed firmware in C++ for ARM based microprocessors with an emphasis on precision motion control and stepper motors.
- Developed firmware that interfaced to memory mapped I/O devices.
- Developed C# libraries for interfacing to low-level functionality using RPC calls over various transports (TCP/IP, CAN, LIN, SPI, I2C, and RS-232).
- Developed embedded controller using Windows Compact Embedded including device drivers (C++ and C), API libraries (C# using managed to unmanaged interops), Board Support Package (C++ and C), applications (C#).
- Authored ISO 9001 documentation including requirements, design, and validation documents.

FIRMWARE ENGINEER

INTERNATIONAL GAMING TECHNOLOGY, Reno, Nevada, U.S.A., July 2007 – November 2008

Word leader in in gaming and lottery systems

- Developed firmware for USB controlled peripherals (C and Assembly) using motion control and PWM algorithms.
- Designed and implemented a networking protocol for a multi-player "community play" game (C++).
- Game development using an internally developed game engine (C++) running on top of QNX operating system.
- Authored technical documentation.
- Developed and maintained testing tools (C#).